Shubham Srivastava

Associate Test Analyst

Jaipur, India | samsrivastava.uptech@gmail.com | +916388789049

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shubham-tester

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

2+ years' Experience looking for a secure a challenging position in an organization which effectively contribute my hard work and to be part of team that dynamically works towards the growth of the organization, Organization which provides scope to update skills in accordance with latest technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Java | JavaScript | Selenium WebDriver | Cypress | Cucumber | API Testing using Postman | Maven | CircleCI | TestNG | GIT | CI/CD | Hybrid Framework | Data Driven Framework | Agile | POM | JIRA.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Associate Test Analyst

Dec 2022 -present

Dotsquares | Jaipur, India

Tech Stack: Java, JavaScript, Eclipse IDE, CircleCI, TestNG, JIRA, Selenium, Cypress, CI/CD, Agile

- Facilitated the front-end automation using Selenium WebDriver with Java.
- Successfully implemented a customized hybrid data driven framework & created automated test cases using TestNG.
- Developed and maintained automated test suites using Cypress and Cucumber.
- Enhanced automation testing framework and create new automation scripts to align with current requirements and change requests.
- Optimized the test execution efficiency by implementing a CI/CD pipeline, resulting decrease in test cycle & significantly improving the execution phase of the testing.
- Analysis of business requirements based on interactions with the product team.
- Collaborated in requirement gathering & analysis, daily scrum meeting, retrospective & client calls.

QA Trainee Apr 2022 - Sep 2022

Tejwik Softech| Lucknow, India

Tech Stack: Rest API, Test Cases, Test Planning, Mobile & Web Testing, JMeter, Agile, Manual Testing

- Requirement gathering Review Scope, SRS & Designs.
- Create Test Strategy & Release Notes.
- Creation and execution of Test Plans.
- Read end-to-end Test Scenarios and create Test Cases.
- Execute all Test Cases to cover the defined businesses' scenarios.
- Cross testing Web, Android, iOS.
- Expertise in Functional Testing, System Testing, Integration Testing, Regression Testing, UAT, Manual Testing & API Testing.

CERTIFICATION

Test Automation Expert (Selenium and TestNG)- ACCELQ

PROJECTS

NarpsUK

Roles & Responsibility:

Team size: 6

- Engineered a customized hybrid data-driven framework leveraging TestNG to support scalable and maintainable automated testing process.
- Facilitated the front-end automation using Selenium WebDriver with Java
- Executed automated test suites to validate the functionality, performance, and compatibility across different browsers and platforms.
- Led the successful implementation of a robust reporting system utilizing extent reporting for detailed analysis.
- Improved test efficiency and accuracy, ensuring the delivery of high-quality web applications.

Red Rooster

Roles & Responsibility:

Team size: 10

- Conducted comprehensive end-to-end testing for the application throughout regression, sanity, and integration testing phases.
- Developed and maintained automated test suites using Cypress and Cucumber.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to define test scenarios and implement feature files using Gherkin syntax.
- Executed automated tests to ensure the functionality, performance, and reliability of critical features.
- Analyzed test results and reported defects, contributing to the improvement of product quality and user experience.
- Worked closely with developers to troubleshoot and resolve issues identified during testing phases.
- Integrated framework with CI/CD pipeline for efficient test execution and seamless regression testing.

SOFT SKILLS

- Communicator
- Collaborator
- Decision-Making
- Time Management
- Problem-Solving

EDUCATION

M.C.A.

B.C.A.

July 2021 - May 2023

DSMNRU, Lucknow

I.G.N.O.U, Lucknow

July 2017 - Dec 2020